<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xml" href="https://lab-work.github.io/feed.xslt.xml"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.2.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://lab-work.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://lab-work.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-04-08T14:37:44-05:00</updated><id>https://lab-work.github.io/</id><title type="html">Work Research Group</title><subtitle>Our research group uses sensing technologies, models, data, and advanced analytics to understand mobility systems so that we can improve them. Our research projects explore the interplay between autonomous vehicles and phantom traffic jams. We also use large mobility datasets to understand urban traffic congestion at city scales, and freight rail traffic at the regional scale. We also build mathematical models and systems theory tools to understand the underlying behavior of traffic flow.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">USDOT research grant for integrated corridor management</title><link href="https://lab-work.github.io/blog/USDOTgrant/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="USDOT research grant for integrated corridor management" /><published>2020-07-21T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-07-21T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://lab-work.github.io/blog/USDOTgrant</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://lab-work.github.io/blog/USDOTgrant/">&lt;p&gt;Professor Work is leading Vanderbilt’s participation in a $5.2 million (total) grant from the US Department of Transportation. The research will seek to improve the effectiveness of integrated corridor management (ICM) systems like the ongoing I-24 Smart Corridor project. The I-24 corridor is a critical part of Nashville’s growing congestion and forms the critical link to Murfreesboro. A variety of ICM strategies are being deployed on the corridor, such as dynamic message signs, changeable speed limits, ramp metering, V2X communication, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project will be supported by a multidisciplinary team: Craig Philip, director of the Vanderbilt Center for Transportation and Operational Resiliency (VECTOR); Janos Sztipanovits, director of the Institute for Software Integrated Systems (ISIS); and Eric Hall, staff engineer at ISIS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read the full announcement at &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.vanderbilt.edu/2020/07/21/vanderbilt-tennessee-department-of-transportation-awarded-grant-from-u-s-department-of-transportation-to-enhance-i-24-smart-corridor-development-with-artificial-intelligence/&quot;&gt;Research News @ Vanderbilt&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">Funding secured along with our partners from the Tennessee Department of Transportation and the Southwest Research Institute.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://lab-work.github.io/images/vu_tdot_swri.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Medium article on Covid-19, transit, and traffic</title><link href="https://lab-work.github.io/blog/COVIDtransit/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Medium article on Covid-19, transit, and traffic" /><published>2020-05-01T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-05-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://lab-work.github.io/blog/COVIDtransit</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://lab-work.github.io/blog/COVIDtransit/">&lt;p&gt;Yue Hu, Will Barbour, and Prof. Work performed an analysis on how vehicle travel times could increase if transit riders switch modes and drive instead, due to Covid-19 concerns. The analysis was performed across all major US metro areas and showed large susceptibility in transit-heavy cities – modest mode switch from transit to personal vehicles could increase all road users’ travel times by 5-10 minutes each way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While very small travel time increases (e.g., less than 5 minutes one-way) may not seem concerning, this could equate to hundreds of thousands of additional hours spent in traffic each day. It certainly highlights the importance of transit in major cities to keep vehicle volumes at manageable levels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read the article &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@barbourww/the-rebound-how-covid-19-could-lead-to-worse-traffic-cb245a5b1da2&quot;&gt;here on Medium&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">Yue Hu, Will Barbour, and Dan Work co-author article on potential traffic impacts of transit reluctance in Covid-19 era</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://lab-work.github.io/images/medium_covid_screen.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">NeurIPS 2019 Workshop - Tackling Climate Change with Machine Learning</title><link href="https://lab-work.github.io/blog/NIPS2019/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="NeurIPS 2019 Workshop - Tackling Climate Change with Machine Learning" /><published>2019-12-14T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2019-12-14T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>https://lab-work.github.io/blog/NIPS2019</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://lab-work.github.io/blog/NIPS2019/">&lt;p&gt;Ph.D. students Yue Hu and Yangbing Wang presented at NeurIPS 2019 Workshop - Tackling Climate Change with Machine Learning on Dec. 14 2019. They presented their work on automatic data cleaning for urban sensor networks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Low cost urban sensing networks enhance our understanding of cites and urban life. IThe impacts of mitigation strategies in communities can be measured at a fine-grained scale, informing context-aware policies and infrastructure design. However, fine-grained city-scale data analysis is complicated by common, tedious data cleaning tasks such as removing outliers and imputing missing data. To address the challenge of data cleaning, this project applies robust low-rank tensor factorization method to automatically correct anomalies and impute missing entries for high-dimensional urban environmental datasets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The method is applied to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://arrayofthings.github.io/&quot;&gt;Array of Things (AoT)&lt;/a&gt; city-scale sensor network. Located in the City of Chicago, IL, AoT collects real time data on the city’s environment and activity with more than 90 nodes. Further analysis of AoT data and its broader usages are also under way.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">Yue Hu and Yanbing Wang presented at NuerIPS 2019 workshop on Automatic Data Cleaning for Urban Sensor Networks.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://lab-work.github.io/images/NIPS2019.JPG" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Future of Urban Transportation</title><link href="https://lab-work.github.io/blog/VU-magazine/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Future of Urban Transportation" /><published>2019-10-31T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-10-31T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://lab-work.github.io/blog/VU-magazine</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://lab-work.github.io/blog/VU-magazine/">&lt;p&gt;A recent article in Vanderbilt Magazine, by award-winning writer Stephen Ornes, featured interviews from Prof. Dan Work, Ph.D. student Will Barbour, and their colleages from Vanderbilt and VECTOR. The article discusses the future of urban transportation, which will necessarily include a multitude of transporation modes in order to accommodate diverse transportation users and a variety of trip types. Vanderbilt continues to invest in enhancing its mobility options under the FutureVU and MoveVU. &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.vanderbilt.edu/vanderbiltmagazine/lane-change-vanderbilt-experts-say-the-future-of-urban-transportation-relies-not-on-one-solution-but-on-many/&quot;&gt;Read the article in Vanderbilt Magazine&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">Dan Work, Will Barbour, and colleages from Vanderbilt and VECTOR are featured in an article on the future of urban transportation.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://lab-work.github.io/images/VU_magazine.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">ASCE STEM Day</title><link href="https://lab-work.github.io/blog/ASCE-STEM/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ASCE STEM Day" /><published>2019-09-29T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-09-29T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://lab-work.github.io/blog/ASCE-STEM</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://lab-work.github.io/blog/ASCE-STEM/">&lt;p&gt;Ph.D. student Will Barbour ran an activity with middle school students from local Nashville schools at a STEM day hosted by Vanderbilt’s student chapter of the American Society of Civil Engineers. The activity focused on bike infrastructure planning and some of the challenges of multimodal urban planning.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">Will Barbour presents on bike infrastructure planning at STEM day hosted by  Vanderbilt ASCE student chapter.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://lab-work.github.io/images/ASCE_STEM_day.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Kansas City Chamber of Commerce</title><link href="https://lab-work.github.io/blog/KCchamber/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Kansas City Chamber of Commerce" /><published>2019-09-24T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-09-24T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://lab-work.github.io/blog/KCchamber</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://lab-work.github.io/blog/KCchamber/">&lt;p&gt;Professor Work, Will Barbour, and Caroline Janssen present excerpts from their research on autonomous vehicles and micromobility data analytics and policy to the delegates from the Kansas City Chamber of Commerce that were visiting Nashville and Vanderbilt. Along with Mark Abkowitz, Janey Camp, Erin Hafkenschiel, and Craig Philip, the session also covered infrastructure resiliency and Vanderbilt’s efforts to improve transportation and mobility options on campus.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">VECTOR presents research on resiliency, micromobility, and autonomous vehicles to Greater Kansas City Chamber of Commerce.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://lab-work.github.io/images/KCCC_combinedLR.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Nicole Gloudemans Presents at Undergraduate Research Fair</title><link href="https://lab-work.github.io/blog/Nikki-Presentation/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Nicole Gloudemans Presents at Undergraduate Research Fair" /><published>2019-09-19T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-09-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://lab-work.github.io/blog/Nikki-Presentation</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://lab-work.github.io/blog/Nikki-Presentation/">&lt;p&gt;Undergraduate student Nicole Gloudemans presented her work from this summer and fall at the Vanderbilt Undergraduate Research Fair on September 19th. Nikki’s presentation highlighted the custom 6-camera mount she designed, prototyped, and tested this summer to advance the lab’s computer vision research efforts.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">Undergraduate student Nicole Gloudemans presented her work from this summer and fall at the Vanderbilt Undergraduate Research Fair on September 19th. Nikki's presentation highlighted the custom 6-camera mount she designed, prototyped, and tested this summer to advance the lab's computer vision research efforts.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://lab-work.github.io/images/nikki-presentation.jpeg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Summer Research Poster Session</title><link href="https://lab-work.github.io/blog/VUSE-posters/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Summer Research Poster Session" /><published>2019-09-05T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-09-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://lab-work.github.io/blog/VUSE-posters</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://lab-work.github.io/blog/VUSE-posters/">&lt;p&gt;Undergraduate researchers Caroline Janssen, Ricardo Sandoval, and Caleb Van Geffen present posters from their summer research at the Vanderbilt School of Engineering Summer Research Poster Session.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project that Caroline presented surveyed legislation regarding micromobility in Nashville and its peer cities, plus how that legislation devoloped over time. Ricardo and Caleb’s project analyzed trips made on shared e-scooters in Nashville to identify high-density areas of trip endpoints that may be suitable for upgrades in parking infrastructure. Both summer projects resulted in conference papers.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">Undergraduate researchers present posters on their summer projects.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://lab-work.github.io/images/VUSE_posters_combined.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Vanderbilt Summer Academy</title><link href="https://lab-work.github.io/blog/VSA/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Vanderbilt Summer Academy" /><published>2019-07-27T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-07-27T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://lab-work.github.io/blog/VSA</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://lab-work.github.io/blog/VSA/">&lt;p&gt;Topics in sensor deployments, smart cities, and data analysis were taught by PhD student Will Barbour at the Vanderbilt Summer Academy in his designed course, “Sensors and Big Data Analysis”. Will had the opportunity to teach gifted high school students from across the United States and abroad during four weeks of class and 120 hours of instruction. Students learned about electrical engineering and building their own sensor prototypes, programming microcontrollers for data collection and control tasks, and data analysis techniques in spreadsheets and Python.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image credit: Vanderbilt Programs for Talented Youth&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">Will Barbour teaches Sensors and Big Data Analysis at Vanderbilt Summer Academy for gifted high school students.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://lab-work.github.io/images/vsa2019.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Tennessean Mobility Op-Ed</title><link href="https://lab-work.github.io/blog/scooters/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tennessean Mobility Op-Ed" /><published>2019-06-24T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-06-24T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://lab-work.github.io/blog/scooters</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://lab-work.github.io/blog/scooters/">&lt;p&gt;Ph.D. student Will Barbour and Prof. Work co-authored an opinion article in the Tennessean, discussing the use of electric scooters in Nashville and the larger mobility challenges of the city. They were joined by their Vanderbilt colleagues Erin Hafkenschiel, Leigh Shoup, and Prof. Craig Philip. The op-ed is titled &lt;strong&gt;Scooters are here to stay in Nashville. We have to make it work.&lt;/strong&gt; It highlights the experiences of Vanderbilt in dealing with mobility challenges around campus, and how this insight might help shape the city’s future transportation approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read the article &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tennessean.com/story/opinion/2019/06/24/scooters-here-stay-nashville/1525691001/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">Will Barbour and Dan Work co-author mobility op-ed in Tennessean with Vanderbilt colleagues</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://lab-work.github.io/images/VUroute_demand.png" /></entry></feed>
