<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xml" href="/feed.xslt.xml"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.2.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-07-03T22:39:00-04:00</updated><id>/</id><title type="html">Work Research Group</title><subtitle>Our research group uses sensing technologies, models, data, and advanced analytics to understand mobility systems so that we can improve them. Our research projects explore the interplay between autonomous vehicles and phantom traffic jams. We also use large mobility datasets to understand urban traffic congestion at city scales, and freight rail traffic at the regional scale. We also build mathematical models and systems theory tools to understand the underlying behavior of traffic flow.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Prof. Work speaks at Smart Cities Summer School at KTH</title><link href="/blog/KTH-smart-cities/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Prof. Work speaks at Smart Cities Summer School at KTH" /><published>2018-07-03T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-07-03T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>/blog/KTH-smart-cities</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/KTH-smart-cities/">&lt;p&gt;Hosted by KTH in Stockholm this Summer School on Smart Cities provides an overview of the latest technical progresses related to smart cities via realistic case studies, as well as present challenges and opportunities for future research and applications. Read more about the program &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.itrl.kth.se/events/summer-school-on-sma/smart-cities-summer-school-2-6-july-2018-1.801116&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">The Integrated Transport Research Lab at the KTH Royal Institute of Technology in Stockholm organized a summer school on smart cities.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/images/KTH2018.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Vanderbilt, Ford team up to measure impacts of Adaptive Cruise Control on traffic</title><link href="/blog/Ford-tests/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Vanderbilt, Ford team up to measure impacts of Adaptive Cruise Control on traffic" /><published>2018-06-27T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-06-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>/blog/Ford-tests</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/Ford-tests/">&lt;p&gt;On June 24-27, Rafi Stern and Dan Work visited the Michigan Proving ground to conduct experiments on adaptive cruise control vehicles and their impacts on traffic flow. See the full story at &lt;a href=&quot;https://abcnews.go.com/US/ford-tech-prevent-phantom-traffic-jams/story?id=56189372&quot;&gt;ABC News&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">Led by Ph.D. student Rafi Stern, we teamed up with Ford at the Michigan Proving Ground to test 36 adaptive cruise control vehicles.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/images/RafiDanFord2018_crop.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Data Analytics for ofo Bike Share</title><link href="/blog/ofo-Analytics/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Data Analytics for ofo Bike Share" /><published>2018-06-21T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-06-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>/blog/ofo-Analytics</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/ofo-Analytics/">&lt;p&gt;Vanderbilt University began a dockless bike share pilot program with ofo in March, 2018. The pilot garnered unprecedented interest amongst students, staff, and faculty in its first month, with over 60,000 rides. Campus administration sought to gain insight from bike data to study how people move throughout campus and to inform decisions on infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Preliminary analytics on the first month’s trips by Ph.D. student Will Barbour revealed that the majority of trips were short rides across campus, but a significant number traveled off campus to surrounding neighborhoods and downtown Nashville. Also highlighted were several high-volume biking corridors through campus that provoke furture study to ensure mobility and safety.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">Vanderbilt looks for insight from dockless bike share. Analytics performed by Ph.D. student Will Barbour.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/images/vu_ofo.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">TUTORIAL ON PHANTOM TRAFFIC JAMS</title><link href="/blog/SIAM2018/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="TUTORIAL ON PHANTOM TRAFFIC JAMS" /><published>2018-06-13T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-06-13T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>/blog/SIAM2018</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/SIAM2018/">&lt;p&gt;On June 13, Prof. Work and Prof. &lt;a href=&quot;https://math.temple.edu/~seibold/&quot;&gt;Benni Seibold&lt;/a&gt; provided a mini-tutorial on the foundations of traffic bottlenecks and phantom traffic jams at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.siam.org/meetings/nwcs18/&quot;&gt;2018 SIAM Conference on Nonlinear Waves and Coherent Structures&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">Prof. Benni Seibold (Temple) and Prof. Work gave a tutorial on the mathematics of phantom jams.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/images/NW-tutorial-2018.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Vist to Hyperloop One</title><link href="/blog/Hyperloop-One/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Vist to Hyperloop One" /><published>2018-06-13T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-06-13T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>/blog/Hyperloop-One</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/Hyperloop-One/">&lt;p&gt;On June 13, Dan Work met with 2017 PhD alum Yanning Li, who is the Autonomous Robotics Engineer at &lt;a href=&quot;https://hyperloop-one.com&quot;&gt;Hyperloop One&lt;/a&gt;. It is great to see the amazing work to build next generation transportation systems, congrats Yanning on the fantastic work!&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">PhD alum Yanning Li gives a tour of Hyperloop One.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/images/YanningDan2018.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Visit by Prof. Benni Seibold</title><link href="/blog/Benni-visit/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Visit by Prof. Benni Seibold" /><published>2018-05-23T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-05-23T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>/blog/Benni-visit</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/Benni-visit/">&lt;p&gt;On May 23 Prof. &lt;a href=&quot;https://math.temple.edu/~seibold/&quot;&gt;Benni Seibold&lt;/a&gt; gave a lecture on 2D Traffic Flow Modeling via Kinetic Models at the Institute for Software Integrated Systems and met with the team to develop new ideas on how to eliminate phantom traffic jams with automated vehicles.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">Prof. Benni Seibold delivers lecture, gets overview of latest vehicle technologies.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/images/Seibold.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">PROF. JUNHO SONG VISTS THE LAB</title><link href="/blog/Junho-visit/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="PROF. JUNHO SONG VISTS THE LAB" /><published>2018-05-21T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-05-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>/blog/Junho-visit</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/Junho-visit/">&lt;p&gt;On May 21, [Prof. Junho Song] (https://systemreliability.wordpress.com/junhosong/) visited the lab and delivered a lecture on “Particle Filter Based Monitoring and Prediction of Spatiotemporal Deterioration Using Successive Measurements of Structural Responses” in the Department of Civil and Environmental Engineering.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">Prof. Junho Song visits the lab to share ideas on resilient infrastructure.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/images/JunhoRafi2018.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">MEMENTO OFFICALLY LAUNCHES!</title><link href="/blog/Memento/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="MEMENTO OFFICALLY LAUNCHES!" /><published>2018-05-14T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-05-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>/blog/Memento</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/Memento/">&lt;p&gt;The project is a collaboration led by &lt;a href=&quot;http://necs.inrialpes.fr/people/mldellemonache/index.html&quot;&gt;Dr. Maria Laura Delle Monache&lt;/a&gt; to develop the next generation of models and systems tools to understand the future of traffic. Maria Laura and &lt;a href=&quot;https://sites.google.com/view/thibault-liard&quot;&gt;Dr. Thibault Laird&lt;/a&gt; will be visiting for one week and one month respectively to launch the project!&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">The project, ModEling autonoMous vEhicles iN Traffic flOw (MEMENTO) is a collaboration between the NeCS lab at CRI Grenoble - Rhone-Alpes and our team in Vanderbilt.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/images/InriaVanderbiltTeam2018.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Prof. Josh Peschel delivers talk on Sensing and Sensemaking</title><link href="/blog/Peshel-visit/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Prof. Josh Peschel delivers talk on Sensing and Sensemaking" /><published>2018-05-08T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-05-08T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>/blog/Peshel-visit</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/Peshel-visit/">&lt;p&gt;On May 8, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.abe.iastate.edu/joshua-peschel/&quot;&gt;Prof. Josh Peschel&lt;/a&gt; visited the lab to share ideas on integrating people into the cyber and physical loop, with applications spanning environmental monitoring to agriculture.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">Prof. Josh Peschel visits lab, discusses cyber physical human systems.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/images/Peschel2018.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">PROF. WORK SPEAKS AT KAVLI FUTURES SYMPOSIUM: SENSING THE CITY</title><link href="/blog/kavli/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="PROF. WORK SPEAKS AT KAVLI FUTURES SYMPOSIUM: SENSING THE CITY" /><published>2018-04-06T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-04-06T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>/blog/kavli</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/kavli/">&lt;p&gt;Motivated by an influx of residents, finite infrastructure capacity, and the rise of a new class of technology-driven transportation services, understanding urban mobility is now a critical concern of major cities worldwide. Prof. Work shared some examples of how the performance of transportation systems is measured today, and how this is likely to change in the near future due to advances in fixed and mobile sensing. See the day two public program &lt;a href=&quot;https://wp.nyu.edu/sensingthecity/recordings/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">Hosted by New York University's Center for Urban Science and Progress, the two-day event spanned a wide array of perspectives on the next generation sensing needed to unlock the potential of smart cities.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/images/kavli2018.png" /></entry></feed>
