<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-02-21T16:49:59-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Work Research Group</title><subtitle>Our research group uses sensing technologies, models, data, and advanced analytics to understand mobility systems so that we can improve them. Our research projects explore the interplay between autonomous vehicles and phantom traffic jams. We also use large mobility datasets to understand urban traffic congestion at city scales, and freight rail traffic at the regional scale. We also build mathematical models and systems theory tools to understand the underlying behavior of traffic flow.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Congratulations to Dr. Derek Gloudemans!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/Derek-defense/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Congratulations to Dr. Derek Gloudemans!" /><published>2023-10-05T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-10-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/Derek-defense</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/Derek-defense/"><![CDATA[Dr. Derek Gloudemans successfully defended his PhD dissertation titled "Interstate 24 MOTION: a multi-camera vehicle tracking instrument for large-scale trajectory extraction" on October 4, 2023. The dissertation chronicles years of dedicated work on the computer vision pipeline for I-24 MOTION, building up from a small feasibility test to a full-scale, computationally efficient 3D tracking system for nearly 300 cameras. Congratulations Derek!]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Derek Gloudemans, I-24 MOTION computer vision researcher, defends his Ph.D.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/images/derek_defense_lr.JPG" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/images/derek_defense_lr.JPG" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">I-24 MOTION shares first public data release</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/I24M-data/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I-24 MOTION shares first public data release" /><published>2023-09-19T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-09-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/I24M-data</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/I24M-data/"><![CDATA[The I-24 MOTION project team released the first dataset from the testbed to the public on September 19. This dataset, codename [INCEPTION v1.0.0](https://i24motion.org/data), contains ten days of data from various traffic scenarios totaling 47 hours. This is the largest high-resolution vehicle trajectory dataset to date on a highway at this 4-mile scale. The project is expected to drive new insight into traffic phenomena, driver behavior, and connected and automated vehicles.

This is the first of many datasets to be produced by I-24 MOTION. Continuous, daily data production is expected to start at the end of 2023. Read more about I-24 MOTION and its data [here](https://i24motion.org).]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ten days of vehicle trajectory data are now available for download by the transportation research community]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/images/I24M_data.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/images/I24M_data.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">I-24 MOTION system article published in Transportation Research Part C</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/I24M-TRC/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I-24 MOTION system article published in Transportation Research Part C" /><published>2023-09-15T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-09-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/I24M-TRC</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/I24M-TRC/"><![CDATA[The first peer-reviewed journal article detailing the entire I-24 MOTION testbed was published in Transportation Research Part C: Emerging Technologies. The [article can be found here](https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0968090X23003005) (pre-print available on [Arxiv](https://arxiv.org/abs/2301.11198)). The dataset described in the TR-C article is now [available for download](https://i24motion.org/data)!]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A comprehensive article detailing the I-24 MOTION testbed has been published in a major transportation journal]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/images/I24M_TRC.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/images/I24M_TRC.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Congratulations to Dr. Yanbing Wang!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/Yanbing-defense/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Congratulations to Dr. Yanbing Wang!" /><published>2023-09-05T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-09-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/Yanbing-defense</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/Yanbing-defense/"><![CDATA[Dr. Yanbing Wang successfully defended her PhD dissertation on "Reconstruction of mixed traffic dynamics at micro and macro scales" on September 4, 2023. The dissertation includes recent work on trajectory post processing that is implemented in the I-24 MOTION software pipeline. Congratulations Yanbing!]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Yanbing Wang, I-24 MOTION researcher, defends her Ph.D.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/images/yanbing_defense.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/images/yanbing_defense.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Servers arrive for I-24 MOTION trajectory generation</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/I24-servers/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Servers arrive for I-24 MOTION trajectory generation" /><published>2022-05-02T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-05-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/I24-servers</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/I24-servers/"><![CDATA[The I-24 MOTION project’s trajectory computation servers were delivered to the Vanderbilt datacenter. Ten servers with graphics processing units (GPUs) will convert video into anonymized trajectory points and an additional server will perform post-processing on trajectories to produce a complete, high-quality dataset comprising each vehicle on the roadway through time and space. Vanderbilt IT will be installing the servers over the coming weeks, with additional system support servers expected this summer.]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The majority of servers that will power the I-24 MOTION computing cluster have been delivered.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/images/i24_servers.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/images/i24_servers.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">I-24 MOTION presentation to The Eastern Transportation Coalition</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/TETC-presentation/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I-24 MOTION presentation to The Eastern Transportation Coalition" /><published>2022-04-28T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-04-28T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/TETC-presentation</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/TETC-presentation/"><![CDATA[<p>Will Barbour and Lee Smith (TDOT) presented during a connected and automated vehicles webinar hosted by The Eastern Transportation Coalition. They discussed the I-24 MOTION testbed and its implications for CAV and human driver trajectory data. Terabytes worth of anonymized trajectory data will start being produced by the testbed, which can then be used by state DOT’s, universities, and industry for CAV and other transportation studies. Watch their presentation below or <a href="https://youtu.be/OJYdYJKcouc?t=2043">on YouTube</a>.</p>

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/OJYdYJKcouc?start=2043" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Vanderbilt and TDOT present on I-24 MOTION and what it means for CAV data to a webinar crowd of over 150.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/images/TETC_presentation.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/images/TETC_presentation.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Construction is progressing well on I-24 MOTION</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/I24-construction/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Construction is progressing well on I-24 MOTION" /><published>2022-03-16T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-03-16T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/I24-construction</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/I24-construction/"><![CDATA[<p>Davis H. Elliot Company is heading up construction work on I-24 MOTION. Work is progressing on ITS communication infrastructure, camera poles, and networking. Construction and testing are expected to conclude in September, 2022. Over ten truckloads of poles, a total of 120 steel sections, are being collected in a staging area. Around 300 cameras and 100 network switches will be delivered to the project over the coming months. Testing of each component is conducted before installation and the completed system will undergo multiple rounds of testing before the end of the project.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Multiple parallel efforts are underway to complete construction and integration of all I-24 MOTION systems ahead of September delivery.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/images/i24_pole_delivery.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/images/i24_pole_delivery.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Work begins on AI Decision Support System for TDOT corridor management</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/AI-DSS/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Work begins on AI Decision Support System for TDOT corridor management" /><published>2021-04-21T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-04-21T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/AI-DSS</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/AI-DSS/"><![CDATA[<p>Funding was secured last year for Vanderbilt’s participation in a $5.2 million (total) grant from the US Department of Transportation to bring artificial intelligence to integrated corridor management (ICM) on I-24. A variety of ICM strategies are being deployed on the corridor, such as dynamic message signs, changeable speed limits, ramp metering, V2X communication, and more – all of which will be accounted for by the AI engine that recommends ICM actions for responding to congestion incidents.</p>

<p>Read more about the project and watch a video on ICM at <a href="https://www.traffictechnologytoday.com/news/traffic-management/tennessee-dot-and-swri-to-develop-ai-traffic-management.html">Traffic Technology International</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[In collaboration with the Southwest Research Institute, we are developing an AI-based decision support tool that will be used for corridor management on I-24.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/images/SwRI_ICM.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/images/SwRI_ICM.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">USDOT research grant for integrated corridor management</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/USDOTgrant/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="USDOT research grant for integrated corridor management" /><published>2020-07-21T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-07-21T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/USDOTgrant</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/USDOTgrant/"><![CDATA[<p>Professor Work is leading Vanderbilt’s participation in a $5.2 million (total) grant from the US Department of Transportation. The research will seek to improve the effectiveness of integrated corridor management (ICM) systems like the ongoing I-24 Smart Corridor project. The I-24 corridor is a critical part of Nashville’s growing congestion and forms the critical link to Murfreesboro. A variety of ICM strategies are being deployed on the corridor, such as dynamic message signs, changeable speed limits, ramp metering, V2X communication, and more.</p>

<p>The project will be supported by a multidisciplinary team: Craig Philip, director of the Vanderbilt Center for Transportation and Operational Resiliency (VECTOR); Janos Sztipanovits, director of the Institute for Software Integrated Systems (ISIS); and Eric Hall, staff engineer at ISIS.</p>

<p>Read the full announcement at <a href="https://news.vanderbilt.edu/2020/07/21/vanderbilt-tennessee-department-of-transportation-awarded-grant-from-u-s-department-of-transportation-to-enhance-i-24-smart-corridor-development-with-artificial-intelligence/">Research News @ Vanderbilt</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Funding secured along with our partners from the Tennessee Department of Transportation and the Southwest Research Institute.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/images/vu_tdot_swri.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/images/vu_tdot_swri.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Medium article on Covid-19, transit, and traffic</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/COVIDtransit/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Medium article on Covid-19, transit, and traffic" /><published>2020-05-01T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-05-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/COVIDtransit</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/COVIDtransit/"><![CDATA[<p>Yue Hu, Will Barbour, and Prof. Work performed an analysis on how vehicle travel times could increase if transit riders switch modes and drive instead, due to Covid-19 concerns. The analysis was performed across all major US metro areas and showed large susceptibility in transit-heavy cities – modest mode switch from transit to personal vehicles could increase all road users’ travel times by 5-10 minutes each way.</p>

<p>While very small travel time increases (e.g., less than 5 minutes one-way) may not seem concerning, this could equate to hundreds of thousands of additional hours spent in traffic each day. It certainly highlights the importance of transit in major cities to keep vehicle volumes at manageable levels.</p>

<p>Read the article <a href="https://medium.com/@barbourww/the-rebound-how-covid-19-could-lead-to-worse-traffic-cb245a5b1da2">here on Medium</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Yue Hu, Will Barbour, and Dan Work co-author article on potential traffic impacts of transit reluctance in Covid-19 era]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/images/medium_covid_screen.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/images/medium_covid_screen.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>